how did you decide that you are German How did you
как ты решил что ты немец Откуда ты
know that you are German Who told you this Well,
узнал что ты немец кто тебе это
because I am German Well,
сказал ну потому что я немец Ну как ты
wait a minute You always lived in the Soviet Union
подожди ты жил всегда в Советском Союзе
Where did you come from, German
Откуда ты немец
Hello Good evening Where are you from
здравствуйте Вечер добрый Вы откуда
Where were you born Where did you live Or Where am I now
А где родился где жил или Где я сейчас
Both Born in Kazakhstan
другое родился в Казахстане
Lived in Siberia in the Far East in Kazakhstan
жил в Сибири на Дальнем Востоке в
And now in Germany Who
Казахстане А сейчас в Германии за кого
will you vote for in the elections on the
будете голосовать на выборах на
weekend
выходных
Well, you can try three
ну можете три
times
раза
I think that you will vote for the AfD
попробовать Я думаю что за афд будете
Not only me I have
голосовать не только я я короче всем
told all my loved ones never
своим близким сказал
Nothing at all does not bother anyone In short I will
ни разу ничего вообще не волнуют всех
grab you by the scruff of the neck and you will all go with me
короче за шкирку возьму и вы со мной все
But the question is why are you all naked
пойдёте А вот вопрос пому все голо
Will you vote for whoever you
голосовать вы будете за того за кого вы
want But I will drag all of you, the infection, to the last one to
хотите Но я вас всех заразы до одного
vote The question is why do all these
притащу голосовать вопрос почему все вот
almost all natives of the USSR who
эти почти все выходцы из Совка которые
howled from Germany support an
выли из Германии поддерживают
alternative for Germany I
альтернативу для
mean Well, they lived from the Soviet Union and left for the
смысле Ну из Советского жили уехали в
normal developed West Why do all
нормальный развитый Запад Почему все
these people almost all vote for an
такие люди почти все голосуют за
alternative for
альтернативу для
Germany No, not almost all but without exception all
Германии Да не почти все а поголовно все
Well  that's why the question is that you have a
ну вот почему во вопрос в том вы себе
poor idea of ​​what it was I
плохо представляете что это за было я
asked why all these people from the
спросил почему вот все эти выходцы из
USSR vote for an alternative for
Совка голосуют за альтернативу для
Germany and because I'll explain if you don't
Германии а потому что объясню если не
interrupt If you're ready to listen
будете перебивать Если готовы выслушать
it won't be so fast I'll try As
это не так быстро будет я попробую Как
briefly as possible
можно короче вот
look my
смотрите мои
parents from
родители из
Kazakhstan took and went to the Far
Казахстана взяли и поехали на Дальний
East just like that they had two children the
Восток просто так двое детей было
grandmother was
бабушка
old they got an apartment they
старая они получили квартиру они
got a job but the grandmother died there They
получили работу но там бабушка умерла
couldn't they left They are from the Far
Они не смогли они уехали Они из Дальнего
East and can you even imagine the Far East can
Востока а Дальний Восток представляете
you even imagine where it is
себе вообще вы себе представляете где
I flew there once or twice I've flown there
это я вот один раз два раза туда летал Я
in short I fly out at 8 am arrive at
короче Вылетаю в 8 утра прилетаю в
6 different times that's how it is
6 разни вре
there you
вот там
go completely nuts
вообще крыша едет
specifically it's like from here now you can just
конкретно это вот как отсюда вот сейчас
take and fly to America you'll also
взять и перелететь в Америку тоже крыша
go nuts you need a little time to deal with
поедет нужно немножко времени чтобы с
it after that they went to
этим вот после этого они поехали в
Siberia in
Сибирь в
Siberia they got a house they got an
Сибири получили дом получили
apartment not even an apartment a house they lived for 4
квартиру даже не квартиру дом жили 4
years that's all they quit from there went to
года всё оттуда уволились поехали в
Kazakhstan in Kazakhstan they built a house for us
Казахстан в Казахстане нам дом построили
we
мы там
lived there where is it where is it all We  Germans
жили где это где это вот всё Мы немцы
understand And then it really started
понимаете А потом началось
When in the winter through here you have a war going on Yes there is electricity there is
Когда зимой чере вот у вас война идт Да
electricity there are power outages yes
электричеством
yes of course in Estonia in Estonia
есть а да да конечно в Эстонии в Эстонии
what should there be power outages in Estonia
что должны в Эстонии быть перебои с
But imagine in our country in
электричеством А вот у нас представьте
the winter in Kazakhstan there was no war
себе зимой в Казахстане войны не
4 or 6 hours a day the
было 4 или 6 часов в сутки включали
electricity was on
электричество
in
в
principle and this all winter What do you
принципе и это всю зиму Как вы
think This is credit there was no war
думаете Это зачётно войны не
Estonian history Why are you voting for an
эстони история Почему голосуете за
alternative for
альтернативу для
Germany listen further cigarettes to us in
Германии слушай дальше сигареты нам в
Kazakhstan not in Russia in Kazakhstan
Казахстане не в России в Казахстане
cigarettes were given out there
сигареты там выдавали
imagine they could not be cut
представляешь их нарезать не
and with such a life I could not help but
могли и с такой жизни я не мог не
leave all structural ties fell apart
уехать все структурные связи распались
so we went to
поэтому мы поехали в
Germany super I did not ask Why did you
Германию супер Я не спрашивал Почему
come I why are you voting for an
приехали Я почему вы голосуете за
alternative for
альтернативу для
Germany why do we
Германии почему мы
all vote without exception
голосуем все без исключения
d only
д только потому
because all Ukrainian refugees or
что все украинские беженцы или
Ukrainian I don’t know what to call them 3
украинские я не знаю как их назвать 3
years lived here not once not
года здесь прожили ни одной разы ни
one at work no no
одной на работе
it’s
нету нет это вы
just you I look out of all my friends
просто я смотри из всех моих знакомых
who are in Germany 10 people
которые в Германии человек 10 вот так
can do this now in  in the head everyone got a job in the
могу сейчас в голове все устроились в
first year of work in the first year Well, well, well,
первый же год работы в первый же год Ну
well, look, we have
ну да ну да ну вот смотри у нас на
1200 people at work So wait, no,
работе 1200 человек Так подожди нет
come on, come on In fact, you said that not a
давай так давай по факту ты сказал что
single Ukrainian works like that from
ни один украинец не работает так из
refugees So you said one Well, you're
беженцев Так ты сказал один Ну ты ты
lying You're just lying
обманываешь Просто ты просто обманываешь
Ukrainians almost all who came
украинцы почти все которые по приезжали
immediately found work, there's really a lot of it, it's
сразу по находили работы реально куча
just you look, you're impudent, just a
это просто ты смотри ты наглый просто
liar, just a
Врун просто
liar Okay, okay, let it be So it's
врун Ну ладно ладно пускай Пусть будет
not important Where did they find work Why are you voting for an
неважно Почему ты голосуешь за
alternative for
альтернативу для
Germany, namely, e,
Германии назва
and you're German Yes, I'm German, my, my parents
э а ты немец Да я немец мои мои родители
Yes, they were in I'll tell you now, my, my, my, a citizen I'm explaining now you're a citizen You're a citizen of Germany, not a citizen of Estonia, but I'm ethnic German, and listen, and here ...
германи вмешательство Вот например
process And you are
вмешивается в политический процесс А ты
already you are now dumb I do not understand I
уже ты сечас неме Не вме Я тебя
am asking you who are you voting for you started
спрашиваю за кого ты голосуешь ты нача
that I have driven you into a corner And you can not
что я тебя загнал в угол Да и не можеш
say So tell me the arguments Why do you
сказать Так скажи аргументы Почему ты
support hell who do you support
поддерживаешь ад кого ты поддерживаешь
Why do you support
Почему ты поддерживаешь
who do you support I support the
кого ты поддерживаешь я поддерживаю
president of Estonia Jonas
президента Эстонии йонаса
Bass I see And who should I vote for I do
баса Понятно А за кого мне голосовать Я
not know You are a citizen of Germany you
не знаю Ты гражданин Германии ты
choose for whom I am asking you for
выбираешь за кого я тебя спрашиваю по
such a
такой
choice I will vote No No you tell me
выбор вать я проголосую Нет Нет ты скажи
why you make such a
почему ты такой делаешь
choice Well because I have seen enough of the
выбор Ну потому что насмотрелся на
Ukrainians who came to us and
украинцев которые к нам приехали и что
what they did And with you they are Well and with you they are And with you they are
что сделали А у вас они Ну а у вас они А
different Well tell me what the
у вас они другие Ну скажи вот что
Ukrainians came And what did they do to you
приехали украинцы Так и что они сделали
Listen how many came to you
с вами Слушай а к вам сколько приехало
also came Yes, in Tallinn I have
тоже приехали да у меня в Таллине вот на
Ukrainians working at work too and what
работе работают тоже украинцы и что
How many came to the country Tell me
Сколько сколько в страну приехало Скажи
what the Ukrainians came to you in
что вот приехали украинцы к вам в
Germany what are they like how many came to you Okay
Германию какие они сколько к вам Ладно
let me be honest you are just a Russian who
давай почесну ты просто русский который
lives in Germany Yes you are looking
живёт в Германии Да ты смотришь
Russian television and you of this cotton wool
Российское телевидение и вас этой ваты
There is simply more than enough of it
Там просто отбавляй
working 30 years The thing is that as
работает 30 ле Дело в том что как
they say you know you can take a person out of the
говорят знаете можно вывести человека из
Soviet Union But it is very difficult to take a Soviet person out of a person this is
Совка Но человек совок из человека
clear about you this is so tell me why you
тебя понятно это так скажи почему ты
Name three reasons why you vote
Назови три причины почему ты голосуешь
for the
за
AfD only after you
афд только после того как ты на мои
answer my questions a few questions
вопросы ответишь вопросов немного
one or two more look I am not a citizen of
один-два ещё раз смотри я не гражданин
your country I do not know what you should
твоей страны Я не знаю за что тебе
vote for you say I vote for the AfD
голосовать ты говоришь я голосую за афд
I say
Я говорю
why Vern And I said that I vote for the ass Yes
почему Верн А я сказала что я голосую
you said that you will be the ass
зад Да ты сказал что зад будешь
and could you say yes yes yes Why why
и мог ты сказать дадада
exactly That's what I'm
Почему почему вот именно Вот мне
interested in with the Americans I say why they
интересно с американцами Я говорю почему
voted for Biden or Trump Yes that's
там голосовали За байдена или трампа Да
why you for the
вот почему ты за
AfD I will answer answer me two questions Let's
афд отвечу ответь мне на два вопроса
ask the first question
Давай первый вопрос статистические
these statistical data are there they are in the public
данные эти есть они в открытом
domain how many Ukrainians came to you
доступе сколько приехало к вам украинцев
in Estonia to Estonia
в Эстонию в Эстонию
Ukrainians Wow Yes On our little
украинцев Вау По да На Нашу маленькую
Estonia that's a lot Wow and imagine
Эстонию это очень много Вау а прикинь у
we have half a million official So and at
нас пол милна официальных Так а у вас
how many people do you have and how many do you have our population
сколько А у вас сколько у нас население
900,000
900.000
people clear
человек понятно
clear What Yes wait well they came they came Come on
понятно Какие Да подожди ну приехали
1l million came to you 1l
приехали Давай 1л млн к вам приехало 1л
million And there are also 10 million there
млн Да ещё там 10 млн
what 201 Look how much money a Ukrainian
что 201 Вот смотри сколько украинский
refugee gets this is also official data they
беженец это тоже официальные данные они
all have how much money a Ukrainian refugee gets in
все есть сколько украинский беженец
your country in Estonia he
получает денег у вас в Эстонии в Эстонии
gets assistance from us 2,000 euros a
получает у нас помощь 2.000 евро в
month how is it distributed
месяц как это распределяется
distributed through social services
распределяется через социальные службы
they get registered at the place of registration no no in
они встают на по месте учёта нет нет
short let's not stick So come on
короче Короче давай не лепим Так давай
look I already answered you so tell me
смотри я тебе уже ответил так скажи
why do you vote how much money do you have in
почему ты голосуешь сколько у вас денег
short explain
короче объясняй
Let's tell you now You just you
Давай сейчас расскажу Ты мне просто ты
just explain to me I am a Ukrainian refugee Yes I
мне просто объясни Я украинский беженец
came to you in Estonia Yes what do I
Да приехал к вам в Эстонию Да что я
get You tell me yes So look
получаю Ты мне скажи да Значит смотри у
we have this one here a
нас этот есть такой вот вот приехал
boy came Yes 19 years old refugee from Mariupol
мальчик Да 19 лет беженец из Мариуполя
No not a boy a man with a
Нет не мальчик мужчина с
family I'll explain again from Mariupol
семьёй ещё раз объясню из Мариуполя
refugee Gena he  Georgian yes Gena last name
беженец Гена он грузин да Гена фамилия
zest dream Yes And this genocide dream he
цедру сни Да И вот этот геноцид сни он
gets 2000 euros he works Went Yes
получает 2000 евро он работать Пошёл Да
but he gets we pay him so that
но он получает мы ему платим для того
he
чтобы он
adapts I
адаптировался в
mean he so that he adapts
смысле он чтобы адаптировал
Well yes they need to rent an apartment there Yes
Ну да им нужно там квартиру снимать Да
because a child
потому что ребёнок
Yes 1488 Ukrainians came to you they
Да к вам приехало по украинцев 1488 они
live how they live Tell me normally they
живут как они живут Расскажи нормально
live I rent rent an apartment they get
живут снимаю снимают квартиру получают
2000 euros they work Yes where do they
2000 евро работают Да откуда они
get 2000 from the budget of Estonia we are
получают 2000 из бюджета Эстонии мы
Estonians I pay taxes Yes and I say so that
эстонцы я плачу налоги Да и говорю чтоб
this
чтоб это
sing to Ukraine part of our taxes goes to
поть Украине часть наших налогов идт на
refugees part goes to help Ukraine
беженцев часть идт на помощь Украине
our brothers Lithuanians in general he in addition to
наши братья литовцы вообще он кроме
taxes even now 2 million euros have already been collected in
налогов даже вот уже 2 млн евро собрали
donations for drones for Ukraine slu A have you
донаты на дроны для Украины слу А
tried to go to war this will be the most creditable Let's
пробовали это будет самое зачётное Давай
try we Now we are preparing to repel
попробуем мы Сейчас готовимся отражать
Russia's attack on Estonia we are preparing and you and
атаку России на Эстонию готовимся и вы и
you we look
вы мы смотри
we when in forty-fifth your Reichstag
мы когда в соро пятом ваш Рейхстаг
was burned because you
сожгли потому что Вы
you yes yes  Soviet who came to
ты да да Советский который приехал в
Germany Yes
Германию Да потому
because now yes you support the AfD party you
что и сейчас да поддержишь партию афд
support the AfD party they
поддерживаешь партию афд они Давай
Come on Why do you know what for me The saddest thing is that
Поче знаешь что для меня Самое печальное
I
что то что я вот ваши
feed and sing yours again look I'm Estonian yes
кормлю и пою ещё раз смотри я эстонец да
you because you talk about Ukrainians
ты потому что ты про украинцев говоришь
you
ты
already so well definitely look Now it's not like that
уже так ну однозначно смотри Теперь ещё
You feed and sing Ukrainians and
так не Ты кормишь и поешь украинцев а
Ukraine protects yours yes So that
Украина защищает твою да Для того чтобы
these Muscovites don't come and Neli you even though you are a
эти не пришли и Нели тебя хоть ты там
Russian German there Yes your wife is shorter than your
русский немец Да твою жену короче твоего
cat and everyone shorter in a circle further Yes no
кота и всех короче по кругу дальше Да не
You feed Ukrainians Yes and Ukrainians at the cost of
Ты кормишь украинцев Да а украинцы ценой
their lives Yes are a shield of Europe
своей жизни Да есть щитом Европы в том
including your Germany Yes you Soviet
числе и твоей Германии Да ты Советская
who sits in Germany there are a
которая сидишь в Германии вас таких
lot of you like that I know a lot of you like that there some
полно Я знаю вас таких полно там часть
of them became normal people Yes but
из них стала нормальными людьми Да но
most of them
большая часть
remained
осталась
Soviet who took
советскими которые вывезли с собой туда
this Russian world with them there a bunch of
вот этот русский мир получили куча
people received citizenship You are a migrant You are a
человек гражданства Ты же мигрант Ты же
migrant you came there 30 years ago
мигрант ты приехал да 30 лет назад туда
Yes you were adapted at the expense of the
Да тебя за счёт адаптировали за счёт
German budget Yes such a one was raised at the
бюджета Германии Да такого вырастили за
expense of the German budget like that  fifth
счёт бюджета Германии вот такую пятую
column and now you sit and I'm there I feed I feed it is
колонну и теперь ты сидишь и такой я там
necessary that people like you
я Кормлю Кормлю надо чтобы таких как ты
all who support Russia and
всех кто поддерживает Россию да
send their
отправить
historical homeland there somewhere in In
историческую родину туда куда-то в
short in short to Saratov like Engels and
Короче короче в Саратов типа Энгельс и
there really so that you know where
вот там реально чтоб ты познал где там
you said an apartment in the Far East they
ты говорил квартиру на Дальнем Востоке
gave you here in the Far East so that you
тебе дали вот на Дальний Восток чтоб ты
go out to your native Khrushchevka get
вышел в свою родную хрущёвку получил там
the keys to it there and sit there vote for
ключики от неё и сидел там голосовал за
Zhirinovsky for Putin and so on
Жириновского за Путина и так дальше Вот
Unfortunately Yes unfortunately there are very
к сожалению Да к сожалению вас таких
many of you like that we understand this and the Germans understand this
очень много мы это понимаем и немцы это
normal you are the main backbone of
нормальные вы и есть основной Костяк вот
this party afd alternative for
этой партии афд альтернатива для
Germany all this post-Soviet
Германии вся вот эта постсоветская
supports
поддерживает
it
её
really citizens of their country as we want so we
реально граждане своей страны как хотим
decide and not
так и реша
so look in
во не так смотри ин
Ma you
Ма ты
Support
Поддержи слу
me who will come to my place
меня на мо место кто прит придут
Ukrainians Syrians and Arabs and
украинцы сирийцы и арабы и
Turks for Germany you were born somewhere there
турки для Германии ты родился где-то там
in Asia Why are you for Germany look a
в Азии Да зачем ты для Германии смотри
Ukrainian who lives here in Europe
украинец который живёт тут в Европе
has more rights to live there than you who
имеет больше прав жить там чем ты
were born in Asia With  what the hell And who are you
родившийся в Азии С какого перепуга А ты
Why are you Asian to Germany
кто такой Почему ты азиат к Германии
What do you have to do with me I'm not
Какое имеешь отношение я не я на
German for a second No no no you're not for a
секундочку немец Нет нет нет ты не на
second Germans are those who are
секундочку немцы - это те кто
VGR for a second I really
вгр вот на секундочку я реально
know how you are in the Soviet Union yes
мы знаем как вы в Советском Союзе да
Children of party workers
Дети партийных работников
entered births so that they would give you a German yes
вписывались рождений чтобы немец тебе
In order to travel with fake
выдали да Для того чтобы по фейковым
documents How will you prove that
документам поехали Как ты докажешь что
you are
ты
German No well here Listen you have a monologue
немец Нет ну вот Слушай у тебя монолог
Yes How many Look let's say how many
Да Сколько Смотри давай так сколько
generations are your ancestors when your ancestors
поколений твои предки когда твои предки
lived in Germany
жили в Германии
when my ancestors lived from 1730 some
когда мои предки жили с 1730 какого-то
whole year since 1700 already in Russia
там целого года с 1700 года уже в России
Yes no in Germany Well and when did they
Да нет в Германии Ну а когда они из
move from Germany to
Германии переехали в
Russia well listen to me tell me when did
Россию ну ты послушай меня скажи когда
they move from Germany to
они из Германии переехали в
Russia here
Россию вот
Listen I have a family book a
Слушай у меня есть родовая книга
genealogy so it was made by an uncle from
родословная так её сделал дядька из
America we
Америки мы
meet as a family once 4 years after the
семьёй встречаемся раз 4 года после
Olympics we haven't met since the last one
Олимпиады после последней не встречались
but again someone has to
но это опять-таки кто-то должен
organize this well very much  you
организовывать это ну очень даже много
have to invest a lot of energy they come here for
энергии вкладывать надо приезжают вот
a second
вот на секундочку
Yes, just imagine This is
Да просто представь
not the first time guys
себе Это не первый раз приезжают ребята
from France come What makes you think that you are German
из Франции С чего ты взял что ты немец
Well, listen further Let's say you lived in guys from Germany come
Ну слушай дальше Давай ты жил
guys from America USA
Германии приезжают ребята из Америки США
come guys from Russia come
приезжают ребята из России приезжают
guys from South Africa this is all this is not our
ребята из ЮАР это всё это не это наш
family for this you need to fly from America
род за это нужно чтобы из Америки
yes Or from South Africa you need to
прилететь да Или из ЮА нужно баблос
pay money wait again from Russia
заплатить подожди ещё раз из России
exactly the same
точно так же
you are German How did you know that you are German
ты немец Откуда ты узнал что ты немец
who told you this well
кто тебе это
because I am German Well, how about you
сказал ну потому что я немец Ну как ты
wait you have always lived in the Soviet Union
подожди ты жил всегда в Советском Союзе
Where did you
Откуда ты немец
come from German And where did you live I live in Estonia I am
взялся А ты где жил я в Эстонии живу я
Estonian
эстонец
and how do you know about your German
а ты откуда знаешь про своих немецких
ancestors my my ancestors Yes, they also
предков мои мои предки Да ещё в
came to the territory of the
тевтонского ордене пришли на территорию
Germans How do you know about this I will say then
немце Откуда ты об это зна я скажу
look in the Church of St. Mary Yes
значит смотри в костёле Святой Марии Да
in the city of de Talen there is a registration book Yes
в городе де тален есть книга записи Да
my great-grandfather Otto von Bauer Yes he was the
мой прадед Отто Фон Бауэр Да был
rector of this
настоятелем этого
church you know a German
костёла знаете немец
so your great-grandfather great-grandfather  yes And what year did
так твой прадед прадед да А в каком году
he live in
он жил в
1925 is the year of birth no no twenty-
1925 это год рождения нет нет двадцать
fifth he was still working in the church year of
пятом он был ещё в костёле работал год
birth ruled
рождени прави
1911 in the PM year he was 14 years old 14 years old Yes he
1911 в ПМ году ему было 14 лет 14 лет Да
was ordained and he and he who was there
посвящён был в Сан и он и он кем там был
at 14 he was an assistant to the rector of the
в 14 лет он был помощником настоятеля
church yes And
костёла да А
in A at 23 years old he became the rector of the church
в А в 23 года стал настоятелем костёла
because he
потому что тот
died and before that, except for his great-grandfather, do you
погиб вот а до этого кроме прадедушки ты
know anyone there is a family book
знае есть родовая книга
maybe you remember was the Master of the
вот может помните был Магистр
Teutonic Yes Master of the Teutonic
тевтонского Да Магистр тевтонского
Order Ulrich von Bauer Yes this is my
ордена ульрих фон Бауер Да это мой
great-great-grandfather Yes in fact he himself was originally
прапрадед Да реально он сам родом сам
from Saxony Yes he was the Master of the Teutonic Order
родом из саксонии Да был магистром
And the Teutonic Order
тевтонского ордена А тевтонский орден -
is a German order Yes Polani Teutonic
это немецкий орден Да полани тевтонский
here on the territory maybe you remember the
вот на территории вот может помните
Battle of Ladoga oh said that
битва на ладожском ое сказал что
What Who said that he was a German
Что Кто сказал что он был немецким
order the Teutonic Order is not
орденом тевтонский орден это есть не
phtonus this is why in Latin it is the
фтонус это по этому по латыни - это
German Teutonic Order - it is a German
немецкий тевтонский орден - это немецкий
order And where did it
орден А откуда он
come from its founder Otto von Bauer Yes
пошёл его основатель Отто Фон Бауэр Да
my
мой
great-great-grandfather was the Pope Yes the Pope
прапрадед папа римский Да папа римский
gave him
выдал ему
in the century in 1375 175 in the Vatican
в веке в 1375 год 175 го в Ватикане
founded in the Vatican the order was issued to Otto von
основал в Ватикане выдан орден Отто фон
Baur on the basis of the fact that I was in the
бауру на основании стон то что я был в
Vatican Estonian Horde in the Vatican an
Ватикане эстонский Орде в Ватикане был
order was issued Yes on the foundation of the Teutonic
выдан ордер Да на основание тевтонского
Order otofon Baur to the founder of the
ордена отофон бауру основателю
Teutonic Order my ancestor yes the
тевтонского ордена моему предку да
territories of the Teutonic
территории тевтонского
Order occupied modern Saxony
ордена занимали современную саксонию
Prussia Libya and Estonia seriously Well not
пруссию Ливию и Эстонию серьёзно Ну не
seriously Well how not seriously I am German I am a
серьёзно Ну как несерьёзно я немец я
native German from the Teutonic And where are
коренной немец из тевтонских А ты откуда
you from the Soviet from the Teutonic No I am
ты из советских из тевтонских Нет я
Soviet Well how are you Soviet Soviet
советс Ну как Советский ты Советский
person you are not German not dude dude dude no
человек ты не немецкий не чувак чувак
no look Germans Stalin
чувак нет нет смотри немцев Сталин
Germans Stalin  shot back in forty-
немцев Сталин расстрелял ещё в сорок
fifth Where are you listen
пятом Откуда ты слушай
listen Teutonic Germans when they appeared
слушай тевтонские немцы когда появились
in
в
Estonia they lived there from birth from
Эстонии они жили там отродясь
birth from what from Rodya from their
отродясь от чего от Родя от своего
Rodya And when they Rodya and from time immemorial they
Родя А когда они Родя и покон веков они
were look Estonia Initially it was
были смотри Эстония Изначально было
Teutonic
тевтонская
so when the Germans appeared there
так когда там появились немцы
were always obligatory would have made sense Look uh those came to
были смыс бы Смотри э пришли те
Finland then look until the third year
Финляндии потом смотри до ри дего года
there was no Estonia at all until the revolution the collapse of the
вообще там нет до революции распада
Russian Empire there was no Estonia
Российской Империи никакой Эстонии не
yes
да вот
really I look I have no noble people absolutely no Come on come on so
реально я смотри я родовитых
where were you
совер нет нет Давай давай так ты где
born look look there is in
родился вот смотри вот смотри есть во
France the city of Strasbourg where you were
Франции город Страсбург где ты
born here in here in France there is a city
родился вот во вот во Франции есть город
sh where you were born Tell me where you were born But
ш где ты родился Скажи где ты родился А
under the city listen
вот под городом вот слушай
further Under Strasbourg [ __ ] not far from
дальше Вот под страсбур гомно недалеко
it there is a city Sever super and now
от него есть город Север супер а теперь
with here and from it literally 10-15 km there is a
с вот а вот от него буквально 10-15 км
city Well a place Luxembourg there
есть город Ну местечко Люксембург там
Ruins there is a family castle more precisely Ruins
Руины там семейный замок точнее Руины
deputy castle you are an Aristocrat Here well I don't
зам замок ты Аристократ Вот вот ну я не
know honestly I don't know most likely
знаю честно говоря не знаю скорее всего
no  So wait if the castle Then there was already an
нет Так подожди если замок Значит уже
Aristocrat Tell me how you Heir to the
Аристократ был Расскажи как ты Наследник
Lord of the castle ended up in Soviet
Властелина замка попал в Советский
Kazakhstan There, in short, there is a place
Казахстана Вот там короче местечко точно
called exactly the same Most likely we are from
так же называется скорее всего мы из
their dense or there together with them I don’t know I
плотн их или там вместе с ними не знаю
can’t establish That’s it I really
не могу установить Вот вот вот реально
can’t I would like to think that I am an Aristocrat
не могу Хотел бы думать что я Аристократ
and then there was what happened next
а там было дальше
as I heard something about this The Night of the
как слышал что-нибудь про это вот Ночь
Long Knives in the army night what a
длинных ножей в армейская ночь какая
waffle Valevskaya yes yes Yes in short they
вафля Валевская да да Да короче там они
all cut each other up and that’s how
всех друг друга порезали и вот как
my ancestors say When was that do you
говорят мои предки Когда это было
remember St. Bartholomew’s Day massacre it’s
помнишь Варфоломеевская ночь это
a little bit different Catholics and
немножко не то это католики и
Protestants were a little bit not where you
протестанты были немножко не там где ты
describe
описываешь
yes exactly there at that time yes In
да именно там именно в то время да В
what year was it Remind me I don’t remember
каком году это было Напомни не помню
exactly Well a long time ago Well when
точно Ну давно Да ну когда
tell me Well it was yes
скажи Ну было да
when Well it was I’m interested now I’ll
когда Ну было Мне сейчас интересно я
take a look right now look Let’s go after that
посмотрю вот смотри Давай после этого
in short they had to they brought against someone
короче им пришлось они против кого-то
they had to run so they
заносили им пришлось бежать так они
ran across and there Germany is nearby they
перебежали а там Германия рядом они
ran across to Germany otherwise they weren’t Germans  they were
перебежали в Германию а то они не Немцы
French they
были французами
were from Strasbourg so you
были они были из страсбурга так Ты
know Well no no stop stop
знаешь Ну нет ну нет перестань перестань
Well 1572
Ну 1572
don't Treat me well I looked at
год не Лечи меня ну вот я посмотрел
Bartholomew 1572 something you
Варфоломей 1572 год что-то ты
a little now listen further they all
немножко вот слушай дальше они все
talked even to this day they
разговаривали даже до сих пор влиза
speak German Well I'm
разговаривают по-немецки Ну вот Серьёзно
telling you seriously Well
тебе говорю
they speak French for bread baguette
Ну они там говорят на хлеб багет
but they speak
по-французски но разговаривают по
German
немецки
who Well those who live in Alsace Damn in
кто Ну те кто в эльзасе живут Блин в
Alsace in Lorraine Tell me about your ancestors
эльзасе в лотаринг Ты про своих предков
like you were born in Kazakhstan
скажи как вот ты родился в Казахстане
your mom dad where were you
твоя мама папа где
born listen my
родились вот слушай мои
ancestors lived in
предки жили
then they screwed up they
вза потом они короче
had to run
накосячили им пришлось
away and then in short one of the
сбежать а потом короче один из
ancestors went to America and the second to
предков поехал в Америку а второй в
Russia and that's where since that time it
Россию и вот там вот с того времени
started there is yes look a small
началось есть да смотри маленькая
inconsistency first if Elsa since that
несостыковочка первая если Эльза с того
time it was France and the Russian night
времени это была Франция и рская ночь
was in France That is you are no longer German
была во Франции То есть ты уже не немец
but French
а Француз
not French Well stop stop how are you
получа не Француз Ну по стоп стоп как ты
German if Alsace  it was French
немец если эльзас это была французская
territory then and the French lived there and the
территория тогда и там жили французы и в
French participated in the St. Bartholomew's Day massacre and it wasn't in France and not in
французы а не это во Франции было а не в
Germany Oh yeah and Zhanar she now
Германии А ну да а Жанар она теперь
wait wait now look
подожди подожди теперь смотри
1572 there was no Russia yet
1572 год ещё никакой России не было ни в
your ancestor couldn't flee to Russia in
какую Россию не мог твой предок бежать в
1572 because Russia didn't
1572 году потому что России тогда не
exist then and he and he wasn't going at that time And
было а он а он не ехал в то время А
when he was going she
когда он ехал его
called him Catherine called him so that was
позвала его позвала Екатерина так это
200 years later yeah and they lived In short
через 200 лет да да а они жили Короче
look so you understand Yeah It was
вот смотри чтоб ты понял Угу Это была то
either French or German territory
ли французская то ли немецкая территория
but Russian speakers lived there in Alsace
но там жили русскоговорящие в эльзасе
They still live there
Они до сих пор там и живут
Russian speakers
русскоговорящие
they are German speakers German speakers Yeah
они немецкоговорящие немецкоговорящие
They still
Угу Они до сих пор там на этом языке
speak that language there their language at
разговаривают на своём языке на
home our ancestors moved to
домашнем наши предки переселились в
another place then one of them went to
другое место потом один из них уехал в
America the other went to
Америку другой уехал в
Russia what's wrong so it turns out
Россию что не так так то получается у
you have stop
тебя стоп
look this makes me smaller than the
смотри от этого я становлюсь меньше
Germans Wait  Stop So do I
немцев Подожди Стоп То есть у тебя я
understand correctly that you have 300 years
правильно понимаю что у тебя э 300 лет
ago in 1700 there 250 years ago some
назад в 1700 там 250 лет назад какой-то
German came to Russia and that's why you
один немец приехал в Россию и ты поэтому
consider yourself a German all the
считаешь себя немцем у него ж все
other wives and children all the wives children
остальные жёны и дети все жёны детей
husbands children were all Russian it
мужья детей все были ж русскими
turns out seriously And where else did he
получается серьёзно А откуда он ещё
get Germans so that they were not there not not not not not not not
немцев взял чтоб их там не были не бы не
And where did he find himself a German wife
были не были не были А где он себе жену
in Russia don't look look there was a collective farm
в России не смотри смотри там был колхоз
they came to steppe stop-stop the collective farm there
они Приезжали в степ стоп-стоп колхоз
was a collective farm under Catherine
был при Екатерине колхоз
Yes so that you understand they came to
Да вот чтоб ты понимал они Приезжали в
PI with their belongings they were given
пь со своим скарбом им выделяли там
plots there in short and they lived there for 100 years
короче наделы и они там жили 100 лет
lived 200 years like that Well look it was
жили 200 лет так Ну смотри это приехал
one of your
один твой
ancestors who came like that and where did his wife
предок так а жена его откуда
come from Well
приехала
either from Germany or from
Ну либо из Германии либо из
Holland from Holland Wow I get it Maybe
Голландии из Голландии Вау понял Может
you are still a Dutch
ты ещё голландский
prince
принц
no Ours are all ours All
нене Наши все наши Все
Germans
немцы
Cool listen you Can you
Прикольно слушай то ты А можешь
tell during the period with  first to
рассказать в период с со первого по
forty-fifth what did your grandfather do
сорок пятый что твой дедушка делал
My grandfather In forty-first they were
Мой дедушка В сорок первом их из
evicted from Saratov in 24
Саратова выселили за 24
hours all their children he was down to the last
часа всех своих детей он до последнего
well up to the last two in short there were
ну до двух последних короче там было
nine children seven children in that army They
девять детей семеро детей в ту армию
went where well yeah those don't matter it's not
Пошли куда ну да те неважно это не
interesting git fought
интересно гит воевали
in Kazakhstan for Hitler and then you ran away it
в Казахстане за Гитлера а то вы убежали
turns out when that is when My grandfather
получается когда то есть когда Мой дед
fought against Hitler yes your grandfather
воевал против Гитлера да твой дед
sat out in Kazakhstan Yes he ran away to
отсиживаться в Казахстане Да убежал в
Kazakhstan Yes he
Казахстан Да с
ran away from Saratov in the sense Well it
Саратова в смысли убежал Ну так
turns out He didn't
получается Он не
fight no he didn't fight Yeah That is it
воевал не не воевал Ага То есть
turns out when our grandfathers shed
получается когда наши деды проливали
blood to stop the Nazi hydra
кровь чтобы остановить нацистскую гидру
your grandfather l hands so that his grandson would
твой дедушка л руки чтобы его внучок
vote for the AfD then yeah Well that's the
голосовал за афд потом
logical
да А ну вот это вот логическое
conclusion it's generally cool yeah yeah
заключение это вообще зачётно дадада Вот
Look my grandfather for a
смотри мой дед на
second in the First World
секундочку в Первую мировую
War
войну
German The First World War with between whom and
немец Первая мировая война с между кем и
who
кем
was what what The First World War who
была что что Первая мировая война кто
fought the Anglo-Saxons and
воевал англосаксы и
Rus Who were the Anglo-Saxons and
Русо Кто там были англосаксы и
Rus Vasa What is this  Vasa Anglo-Saxons
ру Васа Это что такое Васа англосаксы
and
а
Anglo-Saxons and How did the First
англосаксы а С чего началась Первая
World War begin do you remember no Yes she said she
мировая война помнишь нет Да говорила
said the principle killed Prince Franz
говорила принцип грохнул принца Франца
Ferdinand understandable understandable and who fought with whom
фердинанда понятно понятно а кто с кем
there in short everyone with everyone there
воевал там короче все со всеми там
Austria Hungary against Serbia Russia
Австрия Венгрия на сербию Россия
joined in and then everyone joined in
вписалась и дальше все по вписывались
Understandable Listen my grandfather
Понятно Вот слушай мой дед в то время
was in Turkey at that time in Trabzon so
был в Турции в траун Трабзон так
so he fought there after that in
так там воевал после этого
short well for Russia well that's probably great great
короче ну за Россию ну это наверно пра
grandfather fought already and not grandfather not grandfather grandfather where
прадед воевал уже а не дед не дед дед де
what year was the child born
какого года дет рождения
and
а
[music]
[музыка]
1970 or 80
1970 или 80
some I don't remember 1900 some
какого-то я уж не помню 1900 какого
maybe or maybe even 0 some year of
может а может быть даже 0 какого-то год
birth again then what year was
рождения ещё раз то какой год
grandfather
деда
1890 some year of birth where what so and what time did the
1890 какой-то год рождения де какой так
world war start in
а мировая война во сколько началась в
what year in what than how old
каком году в чем чем то сколько твоему
was your grandfather when he fought in Trabzon in Turkey
деду было когда он в трабзоне в Турции
Well he already fought at a mature
воевал Ну он уже воевал в зрелом
age Yes How old how old is he  it
возрасте Да Сколько сколько ему
was I don't remember I don't remember when my grandfather
было я не помню я не помню когда мой дед
was born Well, I mean, look, it turns out he
родился Ну то есть смотри получается ему
was 17 years old or something Well, something
что было 17 лет что
like that, yeah Well, maybe he was 20
ли Ну типа того да Ну ну может быть 20
years old Maybe he was 21 But he was young He was
лет было может быть 21 но он молодой был
really young
реально молодой был
[music]
[музыка]
yeah yeah yeah Such a thing happened to his life Yeah, yeah, that
да да да на его жизнь такое прило
's how it was And against Hitler
Да вот да вот как так а а против Гитлера
Why didn't
Почему не воевал
grandfather fight Listen, it's just because they were
дедушка А слушай а просто потому что их
taken away from the area where they lived in 24 hours
за 24 часа увезли из того района где они
Why didn't he say I want to
жили А почему он не сказал я хочу против
go fight against the Nazi hydra Why didn't he
нацистской гидры пойти воевать почему он
say Listen, what do you
сказал Слушай а как ты
think, have you heard about Nikolai Stella, yeah And
думаешь ты слышал про Николая Стела да И
what And what did he do, the pilot allowed his
что И что он сделал лётчик допустил свой
plane, in short, to hit this enemy
самолёт короче на этого на вражескую
column, the first air
колонну первый воздушный
ram, right Listen, what do you think his
таран правильно А слушай Как ты думаешь
nationality is, he's your
он кто по национальности он твой
relative, what nationality is he
родственник кто он по национальности
Moldovan Well, then it's clear yeah yeah And
молдаванин А ну тогда понятно да да
in my family, in short,
а у меня в родне
in my
реально в моём
family, there's an uncle, he graduated from a
роде дядька он закончил 21
military
июня военную
school on June 21st Junior
училище Младший
lieutenant Well, that is, the gun is so
лейтенант Ну то есть по пушка так
super cool, half  and why didn't your grandfather
супер круто пол а почему твой дед не
fight grandfather
воевал дед
Listen he went to his
Слушай поехал по
destination Well, to the Kiev front And the
назначению Ну на Киевский фронт А на
next day they turned him away they gave him a ticket
следующий день его завернули дали билет
and here's my uncle he wasn't alone but two
и вот мой дядька он был не один и двое
so they went all the way to
было так они
Kazakhstan Wow
короче ажк Казахстан
he that is he went
уехали Ничего себе он то есть он поехал
to the front they turned him away he says go to
на фронт ему развернули говорит едь в
Kazakhstan you're not needed at the front Yes
Казахстан не нужен ты на фронте Да
because they were Germans they were excluded
потому что они были немцы их исключили
from
из
this
это
Imagine not only that not only that I'll
Прикинь мало того мало того я тебе ещё
tell you other things what do you think
другие вещи расскажу как ты думаешь
what
сколько
percentage the war was in Ukraine
процентов война была на Украине
right what does it mean What
правильно что значит Сколько
percentage What percentage of the population in
процентов Сколько процентов населения в
Ukraine died a lot in each
Украине погибло очень много в каждом
village the number of
селе количество
dead Well and how much is that I don't know
погибших Ну а сколько это с не знаю
several million there about 10 million
несколько миллионов там с 10 млн
Understandably 10 million And how many
Понятно 10 млн А сколько там жило
millions of Ukrainians lived there how many died about the
миллионов украинцев сколько погибло про
dead in percentage terms
поги в процентном соотношении
14.88 about this has long been
14,88 про это уже давно
calculated how many
посчитали сколько
14.88 about the population died And in
14,88 про населения погибло А в
Belarus how many died is also
Белорусии сколько погибло тоже
approximately the same percentage
приблизительно такой же процент
more many times more so this is this I'm
больше в разы больше так это это это я
telling you seriously Super so super so
тебе серьёзно говорю Супер так супер так
Why your  grandfather did not
Почему твой дед не
fight so I'll explain to
воевал так вот Объясняю
you on their territories there was a war
тебе на их территориях была война
Yes and on the
Да а на
territory of, let's say, the Soviet
территории э скажем так Советской
Republic of Germans there was no war
Республики немцев войны не было
and do you know what percentage of the German
а знаешь сколько процентов немецкого
population died
населения погибло
how many censuses were there before the war
сколько до войны была перепись
Yes 2 million Germans super then who did your
Да 2 милна немцев супер то с кем твой
grandfather
дед
fight with after the war after the war
воевал после войны после войны
Listen less than 1
Слушай меньше 1
million B
милна В
[music]
[музыка]
after the war they
после войны
made less than a million Germans they said
сделали меньше миллиона немцев сказали
that they were Germans and
что они немцы и
that well and that is on the territory of
что ну и что то есть на территории
Ukraine and Belarus There was a war
Украины и Белоруссии Шла война погибло
either 14 or
то ли 14 то ли
30% died on the territory of the Germans there was no war
30% на территории немцев войны не было
but
но
50 died more than 50%
погибло 50 больше 50%
Imagine Horror and from what did they
Прикинь Ужас а от чего они
die in the sense we or you or we you from
погибли в смысле мы или вы или мы вы от
what did they die
чего
and there was still an army there what And
погибли а там была ещё туда армия что А
that army was there you don't know about it from
ту армия там была ты про это не зна от
labor your grandfather died
труда твой дед умер
understood then look did I understand correctly that My
понял то смотри я правильно понял что
grandfather fought in the war against Hitler And
Мой дед воевал на войне против Гитлера А
your grandfather just worked In the rear
твой дед просто трудился В тылу
Yes My grandfather fought in Ukraine against
Да Мой дед воевал на Украине против
Hitler And your grandfather or what come on
Гитлера А твой дед или что давай так
look grandfathers  Ukrainians fought against
смотри деды украинцев воевали против
Hitler And your grandfather is Chile there in short
Гитлера А твой дед себе Чили там короче
in Kazakhstan yes So that later you
в Казахстане да Для того чтобы потом ты
could go to Germany and tell that
выехал в Германию и рассказывал что эти
you support these Ukrainians our
украинцев ты содержит
grandfathers our grandfathers shed blood for
наши деды наши деды проливали кровь за
your cowardly grandfathers who hid
твоих трусливых дедов которые прятались
from Hitler all the way in Kazakhstan yes our
от Гитлера аж в Казахстане да наши деды
Ukrainian grandfathers stopped him our grandfathers
украинские остановили его наши деды
reached Berlin ours liberated him so that
дошли до Берлина наши освободили его для
later your grandfather would make
того чтобы потом твой дед настрогал
such scumbags like you they went there damn it
таких сков как ты они выехали туда блин
to Germany and screamed for the AfD
в Германию и Орали за афд
mat of Ukrainian refugees that's
мат э украинских беженцев вот
how I understood And who are you by nationality
так понял А ты кто вообще по нации
explain a
обясни
Jew you are a Jew I am a Jew and you are
еврей ты еврей я еврей а а ты
here Because you are German Yes you are
здесь Потому что ты немец Да несёшь
responsible for the murder of
ответственность за убийство Гитлером
my fellow tribesmen by Hitler Yes my great-great-grandfather
моих соплеменников Да мой прапрадедушка
Yes he was and died in a concentration camp Why is your
Да был да погиб в концлагере Почему твой
grandfather
дед
his And what do you do as a Jew I am in a
его А ты кем работаешь еврей Я в
synagogue where I work in a synagogue
синагоге где В синагоге
and you are a believer Yes what Listen listen are there
а ты верующий Да а что Слушай слушай а у
wars in your homeland No my homeland is
тебя на родине войны Нет моя родина
Germany Well you are a Jew yes Well I am from
Германия Ну а ты же еврей да Ну родом из
Germany Listen well I understand  it's clear there are no
Германии Слушай а ну понятно понятно
words before that you were von Theodor
слов нету до этого ты был фон Теодор
Baur so he so yes Well he was a Jew Well the
баур так он так да Ну он был евреем Ну
organizer of the WTO he was a Jew that's it yes
организатор ти ВТО ор он еврей был вот
look my friend your homeland
смотри мил Друг ты твою Родину
from Munich Yes we are from Munich
из Мюнхена Да мы из мюнхенский
Munich Jews Well such and such well you are a
мюнхенские евреи А ну такие-то ну ты же
Jew Yes we we live look we live in
еврей Да мы мы живём смотри мы живём в
Munich
Мюнхене
a third of the 6th century before the Germans lived in
треть VI века раньше немцев жили в
Munich Well don't trend and if you are a Jew
Мюнхене Ну не тренди ты а если ты еврей
and your Jewish homeland some Arabs
и твою еврейскую родину какие-то арабы
there on wait what homeland E don't wait
там на подожди какую родину Э не подожди
this is you not this you didn't understand
это ты не это ты не понял
Jews in Israel from the territory of Germany in the
ев при в израль с территории Германии в
century BC Look Open open
веке до нашей эры Посмотри Открой открой
Talmud look it's written Yes our land
Талмуд посмотри записано Да Земля наша
was between the Rhine and Labai and
была между рейном и лабай жили и спокон
our Jewish tribes lived and from time immemorial and when in the
веком наши еврейские племена и когда в
2nd century BC Gaius Julius Caesar
II веке до нашей эры Да Гай Юлий Цезарь
went to war
пошёл войной
with Germany then some of our tribes
на германику тогда сть наших плем
fled there to the Middle East and
убежала туда на ближний Восток и
settled among the Arabs founded the city of
поселилась среди арабов основала город
Jerusalem And we, we are the legitimate Lords of
Иерусалим А мы мы законные Властелины
Germany, do you live now on our
германи ты живёшь сейча на нашей
Jewish land
Еврейской земле
And what city do you live in
А ты в каком городе
And just like that Well, I,
живёшь А ка раз Ну я
you live on the Jewish
я вот ты живёшь Еврейской
land Wow, seriously You came, you, look, you are some kind of incomprehensible Nomad Lived in the Kazakh steppes Lived in the Far East You still live on the lands of foreign peoples Now you live on our Jewish land Where are you in Frankfurt in
земле живёшь Где ты во Франкфурте в
Munich in Dresden Where are you And listen,
Мюнхене в Дрездене где ты А слушай а
how far does your Jewish land
ваша еврейская Земля до каких пор
stretch And the Biysk Peninsula is
простра ется и Бийский полуостров это
also where As they say, where where the
тоже там где Как говорится там где там
foot of a Jewish Rabbi steps, there is the
где ступает нога еврейского Равина там
Jewish land Yes,
еврейская Земля Да
but look, I was in Prague, so there is such a
а вот смотри я был праг так там такое
cool cemetery, you were buried there in 14
зачётное кладбище вот вас там в 14
E. You know
э зна
why, and there was such a joke there Well,
сами и ложили почему а там такой прикол
that is, not a joke, but as soon as a
был ну то есть не прикол а как только
person dies within 24 hours, he must be
человек умер в течение суток его нужно
buried
похоронить
And well, in Jewish style, that's how it is accepted with you  such a
и Ну по-еврейски у вас так принято такой
custom such a
обы такой у вас
custom tell me about Prague I
обычай рассказывай про Прагу
wonder imagine the city is
Интересно а прикинь город
enemies what to do and a person
врагами что делать а человек
died and in 24 hours you have to put in the ground
умер а в 24 часа надо положить в землю
bury what to
закопать что
do And such is the Czech Republic such and such Jews
делать А такие это Чехия такие-то евреи
in Prague are besieging them there are Germans
в Праге осаждают их там немцы
or
или
kni can leave and
кни могут выехать и
understand VM was the Siege of Prague by the Germans
поним ВМ году была Осада Праги немцами
or
или
Austria you I have no
Австрия ты Я без
idea I only know one thing I was in that
понятия Я знаю только одно я был на том
cemetery Where in Prague Yes in the city center
кладбище Где в Праге Да в центре города
in 14
в 14
floors du buried yes Well where to go
этажей ду закапывали да Ну а куда
ate such a tradition so it is necessary
деваться ели такая традиция так нужно
if without options
если без вариантов
and nowhere to leave you can
а выехать некуда
go to Prague you can see
можешь поехать в Прагу можешь посмотреть
Let me confess to you I am not German and not a
Давай я тебе признаюсь я не немец и не
Jew I myself am Russian who lives in
еврей я сам русский который живёт в
Estonia I am Russian and a and why are you so
Эстонии я русский а а а что ты такой
beaten And I was interested Look I'm
биты А мне было интересно Смотри я
pretending I'm interested in how people
притворяюсь Вот мне интересно как люди
from Germany who support our
из Германии которые поддерживают нашу
Russia how they react to other
Россию как они реагируют на другие
nationalities
национальности пожи сго
please explain to me
вот обясни мне
why Russia suddenly speaks Russian to me
что с какого перепуга Россия мне вдруг
we speak the same Russian language
русски мы на одном русском языке говорим
you are from the Russian world Well, well  Well, you
ты из русского мира Ну ну ты ж по-русски
speak Russian, that means everything We are the Russian world,
говоришь значит всё Мы русский мир
not you, this is you, this is for no Wait, look,
не ты это ты это за не Подожди смотри
come on, the Russian queen Catherine
давай русская царица Катерина тебя ж
brought you, yes, like your ancestors brought you
привезла да типа твоих предков привезла
to Russia, you were, give it to me, Russian Your
в Россию
grandfather fought for Russia You are Russian, for what reason, for what reason Well,
ты был поддай русский Твой твой дед за
look, your
какого перепуга Ну смотри давай так твой
grandfather was a subject of the Russian
дед был подданным Российской
Empire, he was Everything, that means he is Russian You speak Russian
империи был Всё значит он русский ты
Why, why do
по-русски говоришь Поче почему русский
you speak Russian Well, I
ты по-русски
say Russian, for what reason, for
говорю русский с какого с
whom Now, tell me, someone who
каго Вот теперь объ мне
came to
приехавший в
Russia and speaks Russian, a
Россию и говорящий по-русски
room, Russian is a state of
рум русский - это состояние
mind, that means
души значит
Russian, stop, stop, what is my
русский стоп стоп стоп какое у меня
citizenship, so citizenship You are a Russian who is a
гражданство так гражданство Ты русский
citizen of Germany, yes,
который гражданином Германии есть
and look, a Russian who came and
да и смотри русский который приехал и
received German citizenship, ONT,
получил гражданство Германии ОНТ ж
Germany, but he is Russian You are Russian I
Германии но он русский Ты
mean, Russian Well, you are Russian, you are Russian, like me, How come I am Russian I am Russian from Estonia You are Russian from
русский В смысле русский Ну ты русский
Germany from Estonia You are Russian How come Well,
Германии из Эстонии Ты русский Каким
because your great-grandfather
образом Ну потому что твои твой прадед
lived in the Russian Empire
жил в Российской империи
True Well He lived, yes Everything, that means he is a subject of
Правда Ну Жил да Всё значит он подданный
Russian  the tsar was then Whose was he
русского царя был значит Чей он был
Russian I mean Russian he was well Whose was he
русский В смысле русский он был ну Чей
he was a subject of the Russian tsar here
он был он подданный русскому царя вот
look here I'll give you a
смо вот смотри я сейчас приведу тебе
Buryat or an Udmurt who is also a
бурята или удмурта который тоже
subject of the Russian tsar Yes they are also
подданный русского царя Да они уже тоже
Russian already Yes they are Russian they speak Russian
русские Да они русские они говорят
already this You ask him Yes they all
уже это Это ты у него спроси Да они все
say that they are
говорят что они
Russian And you ask him again Yes I
русские А ты спроси его ещё Да я
ask what faith he is what faith he is and
спрашиваю какой он Веры какой он веры а
he can be a faith at least I don't know even a
он может быть Вера хоть не знаю хоть
Buddhist but he is Russian at least an atheist but he is
буддист но он русский хоть атеист но он
Russian that is a Chechen who Well
русский то есть чеченец который Ну
Ramzan Kadyrov is Russian he
Рамзан Кадыров русский он по-русски
speaks Russian Well yes Well yes
говорит Ну да Ну да
definitely Well listen it's cool
однозначно Ну слушай это ведь зачётно
when you speak one of the five
когда ты говоришь на одном из пяти
international
международных
languages ​​I'll tell you I'll reveal a great secret Yes
языков те скажу Открою Великую тайну Да
German is not included in these Five
вот вот немецкий не входит в эти Пять
languages ​​Correct Because we are Russian Yes
языков Правильно Потому что мы русские
our Russian queen Catherine ruled Germany
Да правили Германией наша русская царица
Yes she brought you Germans there
Катерина Да она немцы вас привозила туда
and settled you in the
и заселял в
steppe you worked for Russian Yes  Well, you worked for the
степи вы работали на русс Да ну вы же на
Russians
русских
No, we worked for ourselves No, for the
работали Нет мы на себя работали нет На
Russians, for the Russian Tsardom, for the Russian
русские на русское Царство на Российскую
Empire And this did not exclude Yes, but it
империю и И это не исключало Да но это
was all
всё было
parity, parity, no parity, you were
паритет паритет никакой паритет вы были
subjects, they could take you, like, yes, and
поданными вас могли взять типа да и
throw you to Trabzon to fight like your
кинуть на Трабзон воевать как твоего
grandfather, that's how they did
дедушку вот
n't take you and throw you, you understand
так так не брали и не кидали понимаешь
You're Russian You're Russian I mean, I'm
Ты русский Ты русский В смысле Я русский
Russian I'm not No, you're Russian Well, let me tell you
русский Ну давай я тебе ещё раз расскажу
my story again Look, I'm a pony, you speak Russian, you
мою Смотри я пони зам
think like a
русски говоришь по-русски мыслишь как
Russian You're
русский Ты
Russian Well, listen, let's talk to you
русский Ну слушай давай с тобой поговори
in German Why are you Russian, don't give me
по-немецки Зачем ты русский не давай на
your native language What's your zero?
своём родном языке Какой у тебя ноле Ты
What language did you speak and you sing to me because
на каком языке общался а ты меня
Yaru, we
пой пото Яру
understand Russian, Russian Look, what language did you speak at
мы русски русски понима Смотри ты в
school, what language did you speak at school,
школе на каком языке говорил в школе на
well,
каком языке гово ну
okay, a Russian who has lived in Germany for 30 years,
окей русский живущий 30 лет
all the
Германии всё
summing up is going to vote, back,
резюмирование собирается голосовать зад
like, squeak,
лайк писка
comment, write to my Telegram right now
комент пись на мий Telegram прямо зараз
axis VN
ось ВН
apok this is very and very important YouTube is busy with
апок це дуже и дуже важливо YouTube заня
us through scarg ORV in your ban and very
нас через скарг ОРВ в твый бан и дуже
many videos I do not show people at times do not
багато видео не показую людям вчасно не
show information about streams so that
показуе информация про стримы тому для
we Mali operational links are
того щоб ми Мали оперативный звязок
written right now and Popik there in
пишиться прямо зараз а Попик там в
telegrams okrim video also interesting and
телеграми окрим видео ще теж цикава и
useful information and we owe you
корисна информация и мы повинни з вами
constant operational links
тримати постийний оперативный звязок
independently in that che will show you about this
незалежно в того чи покаже вам про це
YouTube Glory to Ukraine
YouTube Слава украини
write and
пиши а